so there are 13 golden rules of the logo
design industry that are essential to know
before you even think about designing
your next logo check out this list and
see what you are missing out on with
the way the design industry is going
learning how to prototype is a no-brainer instead
of putting flat files in front of your team
manager or client imagine being able to hand
them a prototype that's so good it feels like
a real app or a website now learn more about
framer later in today's video so firstly the
dynamic application we are in 2021 and gone
were the days where a logo was a static design
these days brands and companies are keen to have
their logo also used in combination with motion
graphics so when you're designing a logo keep
in mind the dynamic application of your design
is it going to translate well to a motion graphic
medium this is something you have to keep in mind
next logo appropriation yes it's obvious that
as example using symbols that will be offensive
to a certain group of people is a bad idea for
a logo but going a little bit deeper than that
as designers we need to make sure the logo is
appropriate for the brand and also the target
market in every single way and it should
just be appropriate to the brand's message
golden rule number three is to make sure you
send your clients a questionnaire in the early
stages of your project your questionnaire doesn't
need to have rooms and rooms of questions you
just need the essentials such as things like what
makes your business different to your competitors
who are you here for and what do you offer your
customers and of course so on there are a few
questions like this that you should have in there
so it's vastly important to aim to design a logo
that is different the differences don't need to
be hugely drastic but the logo is the brand's
face in their respective industry and so it does
need to stand out in a crowd of similar faces
golden rule number five is that the logo shouldn't
be too literal an example here is a light bulb for
an electrical company the logo isn't here to show
the audience what the brand does that is a pretty
common misconception the logo is there to be
memorable and to be a trigger of recognition
within the consumer speaking of which golden rule
number six is that the logo should be memorable
this is one of the most important golden rules
on this list today and simplicity does breed
recognition and recognition means the brand
will remain in the minds of the consumer
which then leads to more business
and more profits for your clients
that is the reason for a logo it's not there
to be a nice pretty design that looks cool
it's just a mental trigger that should
hook itself into the minds of the consumer
logo design golden rule number seven is to have
a strict design process and to stick to it so
something along the lines of client interactions
leading on to research and mood boarding initial
design concepts initial designs and then
refinement to the final design solution
so yeah work out your process and what works
best for you and then just stick to that process
number eight is to design the logo in black
and white first sure you have to have some
ideas of colors that will be decided in
the early stages of your research phases
but when it comes to designing the logo
always start in black and white first
this allows you to focus on the logo mark
shape and construction without any color bias
golden rule number nine is to remind yourself
that the logo design is not a brand design the
logo is just one element of a brand identity it's
like one cog in a machine of many moving parts
the logo should work in harmony and
consistency with the overall brand identity
if this fails to happen the logo is going
to create mass confusion within the target
market and the entire identity won't function
anymore rule number 10 is to get a second opinion
now this is so important because we can often
get so sucked into our designs and the process
that we give feelings and emotion to our creations
that can become attachments somebody else can see
the design objectively and for what it actually
is which after 50 hours of looking at something
is pretty difficult to do as a designer but if
you don't have someone to ask their opinion of
you can always just leave your design for a day or
two and then come back to it with a fresh new look
number 11 relates to the interaction between
logo type and also the logo mark if your logo
does have a logo mark then it really should
work in harmony with your text there is no
use having a playful and soft logo mark symbol
coupled with a serious and rigid serif font
both of the assets should work together and
express the intended message golden rule number 12
is to remember the target market always the target
market should be established in research phases
and this is the main group of people who are
going to view your design and so you need to
tailor that design to them specifically every
decision you make should have them in mind
so when you're thinking about typography choices
color choices layout and so on these should all
appeal to that selective group of people and
finally golden rule number 13 is of course
make sure your logo is a vector there is
absolutely no excuse or good reason as to
why your logo should be a rash to file vectors
scale up and down literally to any size and they
still retain their quality the sponsor of today's
video framer is a no code free to use tool making
it easy for anyone to become a prototyper now
their mission is to help you get closer for real
create your own smart components complete with
multiple states without any code as well as drop
in pre-built components with the insert menu and
make your own delightful custom animations 100
visually so in just a couple of hours
you could have a new skill that helps you
stand out from the crowd sign up to framer for
free at framer.com forward slash satori graphics
and that link is down in the description box
below if you want to learn more about logo
designing do click a video on screen and until
next time guys design your future today peace